# Spencer J. Nolton

# C# .NET Full Stack Developer

sjnolton@gmail.com | (586) 556-1764 | Royal Oak, MI

Website: <u>nolto1sj.github.io</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/spencernolton/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/nolto1si">https://github.com/nolto1si</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Life-long learner that is dedicated to the evolving industry of software development. After 6 years studying and practicing education, I have discovered that my greatest learning potential is in software development. There are many parallels between the endless learning curve of a professional musician and a professional developer. Once I realized this, I enrolled in the Grand Circus C# .NET bootcamp where I have developed console applications, web applications, and APIs. This experience provides intense motivation to continue exploring the possibilities of code outside of class time, and I am excited to take that motivation further to pursue this career.

# **EDUCATION**

Grand Circus Coding Bootcamp - Detroit, MI June 2022 - December 2022 Full Stack C# .NET Certificate Notable Projects

Boots N' Cats: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iQ32I69Ij w

• Full-Stack web app using Spotify's Web API as well as our own.

Library Terminal: https://github.com/nolto1sj/Library-Terminal

• Simulates an electronic library in a C# console application.

Text-Based-Adventure: https://github.com/switch201/Text-Based-Adventure

• Contributor and consultant for a large-scale text-based video game.

Central Michigan University - Mount Pleasant, MI August 2015 – May 2020

Bachelor's Degree in Music Education

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

• C#

• .NET Core

• ASP.NET

• Angular/Typescript

• Git/GitHub

• SQL

MVC

• Entity Framework

• HTML/CSS

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager

Dessert Oasis Coffee Roasters, Royal Oak, MI

August 2021 – Present

- Managing team workflow; addressing lapses in work, effectively communicating w/ coworkers & mgmt.
- Contributing to & working on various collaborative projects around the cafe. establishing systems/structures.
- Maintaining inventory numbers & replenishing stock on both a weekly & monthly basis.

Elementary Music Teacher

Clarkston Community Schools, Clarkston, MI

October 2020 - August 2021

- Taught general music to students Pre-K through 5th grade.
- Developed new and unique instructional opportunities for students in an evolving environment.
- Collaborated with teachers district-wide on improving the instructional potential of Clarkston's music program.